<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://influx.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://influx.com/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-06T03:23:22+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Customer Support Blog</title><subtitle>Influx customer support blog - discover actionable and accessible ideas on how to delight, grow and cultivate your audience from support leaders.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What is ‘Support as a Service’ and how can it help your business grow? (2023)</title><link href="https://influx.com/blog/what-is-support-as-a-service" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is ‘Support as a Service’ and how can it help your business grow? (2023)" /><published>2023-07-06T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-06T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/what-is-support-as-a-service-and-how-can-it-help-your-business-grow-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://influx.com/blog/what-is-support-as-a-service"><![CDATA[<p>‘Support as a Service’ is a pay-per-response outsourced customer support solution that allows you to offer 24/7 support in a simple month-to-month format.</p>

<h2 id="support-as-a-service-benefits-and-features">‘Support as a Service’ benefits and features</h2>

<p>‘Support as a Service’ give you a dynamic and cost-effective support solution designed to fill coverage gaps and augment existing teams.</p>

<p>With its elastic pay per response model, it’s a simple solution for clearing backlogs, providing after-hours support or managing peak periods with flexibility and speed.</p>

<h3 id="1-elastic-pay-per-response-model">1. Elastic pay per response model</h3>

<p>With ‘Support as a Service’, you only pay per response, with all management, training and operations included. You only pay when an agent responds to one of your customers - no unused agents.</p>

<h3 id="2-management-and-training-included">2. Management and training included: </h3>

<p>‘Support as a Service’ comes with professional management and training, ensuring high-quality support for your customers. Every plan includes a shared team leader, who’s managed by an experienced support manager. Though you’re only paying per response, you’re tapping into a larger support org that can flex up and down, add hours, add scope, cut back as you need it.</p>

<h3 id="3-dynamic-rostering">3. Dynamic rostering</h3>

<p>Whether you need additional support during peak periods or want to reduce resources during slower periods, dynamic rostering allows you to scale your support team up or down, weekly, based on your needs, providing the right level of support at any given time and avoiding unused support capacity. CFOs love it!</p>

<h3 id="4-month-to-month-invoicing">4. Month to month invoicing</h3>

<p>Enjoy the convenience of month-to-month invoicing, giving you the flexibility to adjust your support services as required, without being tied to long-term contracts.</p>

<h3 id="5-follow-the-sun-model">5. Follow the sun model</h3>

<p>‘Support as a Service’ follows a global approach, ensuring there are no graveyard shifts for your agents. This results in happier agents, leading to better customer experiences.</p>

<h3 id="6-quick-launch">6. Quick launch</h3>

<p>You can expect a quick launch with ‘Support as a Service’ in just one week. This fast turnaround time allows you to start providing efficient support to your customers promptly, without unnecessary delays.</p>

<h2 id="support-as-a-service-vs-dedicated-agent">‘Support as a Service’ vs. Dedicated Agent</h2>

<h3 id="coverage">Coverage</h3>

<p>‘Support as a Service’ provides support coverage 7 days a week, that includes weekends. <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/dedicated-support-teams">A dedicated agent</a>, however, works 5 days a week, aligning with regular business hours. Seven-day coverage ensures customer inquiries are promptly addressed, leading to improved customer satisfaction and loyalty.</p>

<h3 id="pricing-models">Pricing models</h3>

<p>With ‘Support as a Service’, you only have to pay for support interactions handled. A dedicated agent requires you to pay a fixed cost per agent, regardless of services rendered. By paying for only actual support provided, your business can eliminate any underutilization concerns.</p>

<p>Dedicated agents and teams however provide consistency in your team, and at large volumes, dedicated agents are usually more cost efficient. They just need to have enough tickets coming into maximize their efficiencies.</p>

<h3 id="contingency-included">Contingency included</h3>

<p>‘Support as a Service’ includes contingency resources to handle unexpected surges and spikes or an agent calling in sick. </p>

<p>With dedicated teams, support managers need to add a contingency layer on top of their fixed team. Some companies actually add ‘Support as a Service’ as the contingency layer on top of an existing dedicated team.</p>

<h3 id="flexibility">Flexibility</h3>

<p>‘Support as a Service’ agents flex daily. If more tickets arrive, the agents will answer more tickets. The service team leader will also dynamically train more agents as they see more inbound volume.</p>

<p>Dedicated teams flex monthly. </p>

<h2 id="the-hybrid-model">‘The Hybrid Model’:</h2>

<p>The Hybrid Model combines both ‘Support as a Service’ and dedicated support teams. This approach allows you to create a tailored support solution that aligns precisely with your specific business needs and objectives.</p>

<p>Assign critical or specialized tasks to dedicated agents, who possess in-depth knowledge of the brand, product, or industry and can handle complex customer inquiries. Their expertise ensures that customers receive specialized assistance, fostering a higher level of satisfaction and resolution.</p>

<p>At the same time, add 24/7 coverage or contingency with ‘Support as a Service’.</p>

<p>By utilizing ‘Support as a Service’, you can provide support coverage at odd hours and weekends to ensure that you have full coverage. You can also use it to handle standard inquiries, freeing up your dedicated agent(s) to focus on more specialized issues. If you face any sudden spikes in demand, ‘Support as a Service’ allows you to serve these customers without any drops in coverage.</p>

<p>The Hybrid Model empowers your business to strike a balance between personalized, dedicated support and the scalability and cost-effectiveness of ‘Support as a Service’.</p>

<h2 id="how-do-brands-use-support-as-a-service">How do brands use ‘Support as a Service’?</h2>

<p>An example of how a brand effectively utilizes ‘Support as a Service’ is by implementing the Hybrid Model. In this approach, the brand employs a dedicated agent who works during normal business hours to handle customer inquiries and support tickets on weekdays. However, during the weekends when the workload may vary or when additional coverage is needed, they leverage ‘Support as a Service’ to ensure uninterrupted customer support. </p>

<p>By adopting this strategy, the brand achieves the best of both worlds: maintaining consistent and personalized support through a dedicated agent during the workweek while extending support coverage to all seven days of the week with the help of ‘Support as a Service’. This hybrid approach optimizes efficiency, responsiveness, and customer satisfaction, allowing the brand to deliver exceptional support tailored to their customers’ needs throughout the entire week.</p>

<h2 id="three-ways-to-purchase-support-as-a-service">Three ways to purchase ‘Support as a Service’</h2>

<p>When it comes to purchasing ‘Support as a Service’, businesses have the flexibility to choose from three distinct options.</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>ASYNC</strong>: Efficient support on-demand, with fast response times and the ability to pay per response, providing cost control and scalability. </li>
  <li><strong>LIVE</strong>: Trained agents are available in real-time to provide immediate support, ensuring quick issue resolution and exceptional customer experiences. </li>
  <li><strong>THE HYBRID MODEL</strong>: Combine the benefits of ‘Support as a Service’ with dedicated agents. This allows businesses to tailor their support solution based on coverage hours, scalability, and specialisation.</li>
</ol>

<p>This three-fold approach provides businesses with the freedom to select the buying model that best aligns with their specific requirements, ensuring optimal support delivery and customer satisfaction.</p>

<h2 id="how-much-does-support-as-a-service-cost">How much does ‘Support as a Service’ cost?</h2>

<p>Currently, Influx offers two distinct plans for ‘Support as a Service’:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>ASYNC</strong>: $999/month minimum spend - 1-2 hour avg response times.</li>
  <li><strong>LIVE</strong>: $1,999/month minimum spend - 2 minute avg response times.</li>
</ul>

<p>All ‘Support as a Service’ plans are pay-per-response at $2.50 per response. <br />Response times are estimated and depend on the scope of coverage needed.</p>

<p>Prices above are for a single region of coverage. </p>

<h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started</h2>

<p>To get started with ‘Support as a Service’, <a href="https://influx.com/get-a-quote">schedule a scoping call here</a> to see if it’s the right fit.</p>]]></content><author><name>Arslan Ahmad</name><email>arslan.ahmad@influx.com</email></author><category term="product" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Support as a Service’ is a pay-per-response outsourced customer support solution that allows you to offer 24/7 support in a simple month-to-month format.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spoonflower case study: 91% CSAT for 3,200~ tickets p/month with scale-up capacity for seasonal spikes</title><link href="https://influx.com/blog/spoonflower-case-study" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spoonflower case study: 91% CSAT for 3,200~ tickets p/month with scale-up capacity for seasonal spikes" /><published>2023-06-28T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-28T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/spoonflower-case-study-91-csat-for-3-200-tickets-p-month-with-scale-up-capacity-for-seasonal-spikes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://influx.com/blog/spoonflower-case-study"><![CDATA[<h2 id="about-spoonflower"><strong>About Spoonflower:</strong></h2>

<p><a href="https://www.spoonflower.com/" target="_blank">Spoonflower</a> is an on-demand digital printing marketplace for custom fabric, wallpaper, and home decor. The brand connects makers and consumers with independent artists around the world, using eco-friendly, sustainable, and scalable manufacturing processes.</p>

<h2 id="influx-team-setup"><strong>Influx team setup:</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li>5 <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/dedicated-support-teams" target="_blank">dedicated agents</a></li>
  <li>Chat and email via Zendesk</li>
  <li>Scale up capacity for seasonal spikes</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="influx-team-results"><strong>Influx team results:</strong></h2>

<ul>
  <li>96% CSAT</li>
  <li>1-minute FRT for chat</li>
  <li>3,200~ tickets p/month</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="getting-started-with-influx"><strong>Getting started with Influx:</strong></h2>

<p>Spoonflower came to Influx in September 2021 in preparation for seasonal spikes from Black Friday through New Year. They needed an additional team to handle ticket spikes during the holidays and ensure a 90%+ CSAT. </p>

<p>The Influx team consists of 5 dedicated agents based in Jamaica with a flexible scale-up of two additional agents for peak season starting each October. The team exceeds the targeted ticket value of 750 tickets p/week, handling 3,200~ tickets p/month with a 1-minute first response time for chat and a 96% CSAT.</p>

<h2 id="testimonial"><strong>Testimonial:</strong></h2>

<p>“<em>Spoonflower has had a consistently great relationship with Influx since the start. Huge kudos to the agents who all achieve/maintain a high CSAT score and exceed their KPIs. We use the Influx team as the benchmark for all customer support at Spoonflower and utilize their feedback for operational and service improvements.</em>”</p>

<p>-Molly Coleman Graven, Customer Service Supervisor at Spoonflower</p>

<h2 id="about-influx"><strong>About Influx: </strong></h2>

<p>Influx provides flexible, on-demand support across channels with all management and training included. Scale coverage up and down as needed with agents ready to go in as little as one week. Ready to try Influx? <a href="https://influx.com/get-a-quote" target="_blank">Contact sales</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mikayla Fuller</name></author><category term="case studies" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[About Spoonflower:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The future of customer support is AI-human collaboration</title><link href="https://influx.com/blog/human-ai-customer-support-collaboration" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The future of customer support is AI-human collaboration" /><published>2023-06-16T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-16T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/the-future-of-customer-support-is-ai-human-collaboration</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://influx.com/blog/human-ai-customer-support-collaboration"><![CDATA[<p>AI is infiltrating every industry and transforming the way we work. What does this mean for <a href="https://influx.com/" target="_blank">human-lead customer support</a>? And does this mean we should immediately adapt? Well, not exactly. Let’s look at the facts.</p>

<h2 id="ai-is-not-a-substitute-for-humans"><strong>AI is not a substitute for humans</strong></h2>

<p>Companies that recently replaced <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/dedicated-support-teams" target="_blank">human-powered support</a> with artificial intelligence are now backpedaling. Take bad customer satisfaction (CSAT) situations, for example. Instances like giving the wrong information to a customer or striking the wrong tone is a frustrating experience for customers simply looking for answers. Chatbots can make the situation worse when it comes to complex problems requiring in-depth levels of decision-making and communication. </p>

<p>There are obvious benefits to chatbots—productive, fast interactions that can reduce cost—but there are also challenges that impact a customer’s experience. Alongside the high error rate of chatbots, they are notoriously difficult to create. Many of the bots struggle to connect with users or perform simple tasks. At the moment, a highly intuitive chatbot cannot replace human interactions because AI doesn’t have the capacity for human-level empathy—a <a href="https://influx.com/blog/building-rapport-for-customer-support-success" target="_blank">necessary soft skill in customer support</a>.</p>

<p>Here’s what OpenAI CEO Sam Altman has to say on the matter. </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I think it’s important to understand and think about GPT-4 as a tool, not a creature, which is easy to get confused, and it’s a tool that people have a great deal of control over and how they use it.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Instead of replacing humans with AI, it should be used to amplify efforts and expand on creativity in a way that saves us time to tackle more critical responsibilities.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/ai-support-blog-1.jpg" alt="" width="1906" height="459" /></p>

<h2 id="using-ai-as-a-tool-not-the-final-solution"><strong>Using AI as a tool, not the final solution</strong></h2>

<p>Consider the accuracy of humans compared to AI. Humans have roughly a 98% accuracy rate—accounting for human error—whereas most well-tuned generative AI tools fall in the 80-90% range. (Risnews) Put side by side, this is pretty surprising, but not really. Modern AI algorithms learn from processing massive amounts of data, which can be imperfect. And besides the fact that AI can be biased, it falls short of emotion, common sense, and creativity. Simply stated: despite learning from large amounts of data, AI lacks context…key information in the customer support world.</p>

<p>Someday AI may surpass human accuracy, but for now, depending on data alone in customer support conversations leaves consumers with a hollow experience. Using collaborative intelligence, we can unlock AI’s full potential to receive the benefits: automation, efficiency, and cost savings. If we take what AI has to offer, employing it carefully and creatively, we marry our latest (and potentially greatest) creation with our uniquely human traits for better results.</p>

<p>The question, then, is how do we use AI as a tool? This looks different for each business and should be approached with mindfulness. Tasks like fact-checking, testing, monitoring, and validating automated software ensure AI is operating within expected boundaries. In the customer support space, merging <a href="https://www.marktechpost.com/2023/04/09/best-ai-based-customer-support-tools-2023/?utm_medium=email&amp;_hsmi=2&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz--3Z6caRuu2-QfFUe27kJaUW2CnEiDYM0kUtkaUbnHzSPpVHRzgfWoN9rY4ruxd4ji-dnn41aulg7U3lwE3n9rVtbCEpI1cdauVjW1DpjIfeQx3BKs&amp;utm_content=2&amp;utm_source=hs_email" target="_blank">the best AI-based support tools</a> with human-centric skills is the most effective way to achieve modern balance.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/ai-support-blog-2.jpg" alt="" width="1906" height="543" /></p>

<h2 id="what-does-the-future-of-customer-support-look-like"><strong>What does the future of customer support look like?</strong></h2>

<p>The future is unknown until we reach it, but based on the current trajectory, we can make a few predictions about what customer support teams should prioritize in the coming months and years. </p>

<h4 id="heres-our-hot-take">Here’s our hot take:</h4>

<ul>
  <li>As the world continues to move digital, human connection becomes more valuable. Consumers will treasure human connection more than ever before. </li>
  <li>Companies with <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/dedicated-support-teams" target="_blank">human customer support representatives</a> gain a competitive advantage over businesses that rely mainly on AI for support.</li>
  <li>The more we talk with bots, the more we’ll crave the depth of human conversation. Talking with a human then becomes a relief.</li>
</ul>

<p>To answer the question, the future of customer support is not AI-driven. It is and always has been human-centric. That isn’t to say that artificial intelligence cannot help us solve problems, but it points to respecting consumers enough to give them the time of day and the space to share their frustrations with someone who will listen. Efficiency will never be worth the price of replacing humans, but that doesn’t mean we can’t use the tools in front of us to keep moving forward.</p>

<h2 id="human-powered-support"><strong>Human-powered support</strong></h2>

<p>Influx uses the follow-the-sun model for global, multilingual support solutions that are 100% human-powered. We can get behind AI as a tool but believe that your customers deserve the attentive care of a human being to assist them. When each support conversation differs from the last, you need an empathetic human on the other end of the line who can relate to a problem and provide tailored solutions.</p>

<p>Our customer support is flexible, on-demand, and scales with your business. Check out our <a href="https://influx.com/brand-match" target="_blank">brand match page</a> to see how we respond to customers exactly how you tell us to. Keep your support human-centric and <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/support-outsourcing" target="_blank">get a quote</a>!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mikayla Fuller</name></author><category term="customer support" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI is infiltrating every industry and transforming the way we work. What does this mean for human-lead customer support? And does this mean we should immediately adapt? Well, not exactly. Let’s look at the facts.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building rapport for customer support success</title><link href="https://influx.com/blog/building-rapport-for-customer-support-success" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building rapport for customer support success" /><published>2023-06-06T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-06T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/building-rapport-for-customer-support-success</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://influx.com/blog/building-rapport-for-customer-support-success"><![CDATA[<p>Delivering <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/enterprise" target="_blank">top-notch customer support</a> for any brand is challenging—people problems are hardly ever one size fits all. They require quick thinking, a good level of EQ, and a whole lot of patience! The big difference between good and exceptional support is ongoing training focused on strengthening soft skills—skills that aren’t always natural or easy to learn but make the biggest impact on efficient communication and building rapport. </p>

<p>In this blog, we talk with Kaydene, our enterprise training expert, about how to build rapport for <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/support-outsourcing" target="_blank">customer support success</a>. Interested in how training on soft skills can impact a customer’s experience? We’ll cover that too. </p>

<h2 id="building-rapport-for-enhanced-experiences"><strong>Building rapport for enhanced experiences</strong></h2>

<p>As a way to build and maintain customer relationships, building rapport creates a friendly and supportive environment for agents and customers. You’ve most likely had a frustrating support experience at least once, and chances are that you’ve also had at least one amazing support interaction. It probably went something like this: an agent established a genuine connection with you that made you feel valued and heard, and most importantly, they helped you resolve the problem. The recipe is simple, but the execution is the hard part. </p>

<p>Some people are extroverts. Some are introverts. Some people are authoritative, while others may have trouble explaining things clearly. Building rapport streamlines conversations with customers of all communication styles and helps to immediately pick up on tone to recognize the customer’s mood. The point is: you’re interacting with a unique human being who has their own feelings, frustrations, and problems. Meet them where they are.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/kaydene-engagement-1.jpg" alt="" width="2053" height="880" /></p>

<h3 id="soft-skills-to-establish-rapport"><strong>Soft skills to establish rapport </strong></h3>

<p>Soft skills are the secret sauce that spice up interactions and help an agent navigate the conversation. The best customer support agents utilize a variety of soft skills to build rapport. Here are a few of our favorites: </p>

<ul>
  <li>Empathy</li>
  <li>Active listening</li>
  <li>Patience</li>
  <li>Clear communication</li>
  <li>Positive attitude</li>
  <li>Problem-solving skills</li>
</ul>

<p>Let’s look at a real-world example:</p>

<p>Customer: “I’ve been having trouble with your product. I’ve tried everything but it keeps freezing.”</p>

<p>Agent: “I understand how frustrating that is and I can help. Just to make sure I’m on the same page, you said you’ve tried troubleshooting already. Could you please walk me through what you’ve tried so far?”</p>

<p>Building rapport is centered around managing the customer journey in every conversation, every day. By strengthening and honing soft skills, representatives can grasp customer concerns and needs more accurately, demonstrate attentiveness and genuine interest, and provide appropriate resolutions for clear and concise exchanges. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/kaydene-active-listening.jpg" alt="" width="2053" height="700" /></p>

<h2 id="the-key-ingredient-for-excellent-support-experiences"><strong>The key ingredient for excellent support experiences </strong></h2>

<p>One of the essential soft skills customer support agents should focus on mastering is empathy, which bridges the gap between your viewpoint and the customer’s. Through training, agents can understand when empathy is needed and when a situation might require compassion. </p>

<h4 id="here-are-kaydenes-simple-questions-to-know-if-agents-need-to-empathize">Here are Kaydene’s simple questions to know if agents need to empathize: </h4>

<ol>
  <li>What is the customer’s concern, issue, or request?</li>
  <li>How has this affected the customer?</li>
  <li>How does the customer feel about it?</li>
</ol>

<p>A negative expression to any of these questions requires empathy, but it doesn’t hurt to always consider what the customer is experiencing, regardless of outward frustration. Knowing when to apologize is one thing, but understanding the customer’s situation by putting yourself in their shoes can go a long way, even if you may have never been in that situation before. It’s simple: if they’re frustrated, you would probably be frustrated too. This understanding removes the barrier, allowing agents to communicate more effectively. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/kaydene-authentic-connection-1.jpg" alt="" width="2053" height="801" /></p>

<p>Overall, soft skills help you to better understand customer needs and expectations, which are necessary for building rapport. Adding a little personality paired with soft skills in support interactions can break the ice and jump straight into the connection. </p>

<h3 id="building-trust-one-conversation-at-a-time"><strong>Building trust, one conversation at a time</strong></h3>

<p>Building rapport is an essential part of customer support that helps to keep customers satisfied. Influx agents are trained to master customer rapport for long-term success and relationship building. We deliver full-service teams with flexible, pay-as-you-go pricing. <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/support-outsourcing" target="_blank">Get a quote now</a>! </p>]]></content><author><name>Mikayla Fuller</name></author><category term="customer support" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delivering top-notch customer support for any brand is challenging—people problems are hardly ever one size fits all. They require quick thinking, a good level of EQ, and a whole lot of patience! The big difference between good and exceptional support is ongoing training focused on strengthening soft skills—skills that aren’t always natural or easy to learn but make the biggest impact on efficient communication and building rapport. ]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 reasons every sales team should have sales assistants</title><link href="https://influx.com/blog/seven-reasons-every-sales-team-should-have-sales-assistants" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 reasons every sales team should have sales assistants" /><published>2023-05-18T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-18T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/7-reasons-every-sales-team-should-have-sales-assistants</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://influx.com/blog/seven-reasons-every-sales-team-should-have-sales-assistants"><![CDATA[<p>Imagine this scenario: ABC Corporation, a rapidly growing technology company, has recently launched an innovative software solution that has gained significant traction in the market. The company’s sales team has been working tirelessly to capitalize on the product’s success and drive sales. However, as demand surges and the customer base expands, they need help to keep up with the workload. </p>

<p>The sales team realizes that they need additional support to maintain momentum and ensure high customer satisfaction. After careful consideration, they hire sales assistants to alleviate the burden on the sales team and facilitate business growth. </p>

<p>This is a specific scenario, but it provides one example of when sales assistants are needed and how they can help a business to increase sales and continue to scale. In this blog, we’ll explore what sales assistants do, when a business needs sales assistants, and how <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/sales-assistants" target="_blank">sales assistants</a> can benefit a team. </p>

<h2 id="the-role-of-sales-assistants"><strong>The role of sales assistants </strong></h2>

<p>As an extra layer of support, sales assistants empower a sales team by playing a proactive role in lead management. Sales assistants contribute to pipeline growth, enabling a sales team to focus on closing deals with qualified prospects and generating more potential opportunities. Assistants can also build and nurture customer relationships, streamline administrative tasks, and analyze sales data to make data-driven decisions.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/sales-team-blog-1.jpg" alt="" width="1906" height="459" /></p>

<h2 id="outsourced-sales-assistants"><strong>Outsourced sales assistants </strong></h2>

<p>Outsourcing sales assistants refers to the practice of hiring sales assistants from a third party to provide support to a sales team. Instead of employing full-time or part-time sales assistants directly within the organization, businesses outsource these roles to external service providers, like <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/sales-assistants" target="_blank">Influx sales assistants</a>, who specialize in digital sales support services for cost optimization and increased lead generation. </p>

<p>Looking for an end-to-end sales solution? Check out <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/dedicated-sales-teams" target="_blank">dedicated sales teams</a>. </p>

<h2 id="does-my-business-need-sales-assistants"><strong>Does my business need sales assistants? </strong></h2>

<p>A business may need to hire sales assistants in various situations, depending on its industry, size, customer base, and specific needs. A business can benefit from sales assistants if a sales team is having difficulty with the following: </p>

<ul>
  <li>It’s challenging to manage a growing customer base or sales targets. </li>
  <li>The sales team could use an extra layer of support to handle their workload effectively. </li>
  <li>If researching potential customers, making initial contact, qualifying leads, and scheduling appointments is taking up too much valuable time.</li>
  <li>If following up on leads or providing post-sales support is too much. </li>
</ul>

<p>If any of these areas start to fall behind or could use backup, <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/sales-assistants" target="_blank">sales assistants</a> can help to strengthen the sales process. By assessing workload, areas of support required, and the potential for enhanced efficiency, businesses can determine when it’s necessary to bring sales assistants on board. The following section covers different ways sales assistants can help alleviate these pain points. </p>

<h2 id="7-reasons-every-sales-team-should-have-sales-assistants"><strong>7 reasons every sales team should have sales assistants</strong></h2>

<p>Sales assistants offer several benefits to sales teams, including: </p>

<h3 id="1-streamlining-sales-processes"><strong>1. Streamlining sales processes</strong></h3>

<p>From proposal and contract preparation to order processing and fulfillment, sales assistants contribute to streamlining sales processes. Their support ensures smoother operations, reducing administrative bottlenecks and enhancing overall efficiency. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/sales-team-blog-2.jpg" alt="" width="1906" height="459" /></p>

<h3 id="2-improved-lead-generation-and-qualification"><strong>2. Improved lead generation and qualification</strong></h3>

<p>A staggering <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/sales/facts-about-your-prospect-you-can-find-in-minutes" target="_blank">50% of sales time</a> is wasted on unproductive prospecting. Sales assistants help with lead generation and prospect efforts, conduct research, and manage initial outreach. By identifying qualified leads and gathering relevant information, the sales team can prioritize their efforts on leads with higher potential, ultimately improving conversion rates.</p>

<h3 id="3-data-management-and-analysis"><strong>3. Data management and analysis </strong></h3>

<p>Sales assistants can help manage and analyze sales data to identify trends, patterns, and opportunities for improvement. Their insights enable the sales team to make data-driven decisions, refine their strategies, and maximize sales performance. </p>

<h3 id="4-productivity-and-time-management"><strong>4. Productivity and time management </strong></h3>

<p>By taking care of administrative tasks, data management, and other support functions, sales assistants free up time for sales professionals to focus on core selling activities. This leads to increased productivity and allows sales teams to use their time more effectively. <a href="https://www.salesforce.com/blog/15-sales-statistics/" target="_blank">Salesforce</a> shares a shocking stat…</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Sales representatives spend only 28% of their week selling, down from 34% in 2018. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>When sales teams are weighed down by manual work, it prevents them from focusing on sales. Sales assistants can help a team focus more time on sales. </p>

<h3 id="5-customer-experience-enhancement"><strong>5. Customer experience enhancement </strong></h3>

<p>Sales assistants play a vital role in creating a smooth customer journey and building positive relationships. Providing personalized customer support, promptly addressing inquiries, and resolving issues improve the customer experience, leading to higher customer satisfaction and loyalty that can help boost future sales. </p>

<h3 id="6-increased-roi"><strong>6. Increased ROI </strong></h3>

<p>Because sales assistants’ contributions are multifaceted, they can work where they are most needed to support the sales team. Their support in sales-related activities contributes to improved sales effectiveness, optimized sales processes, and unlocking potential revenue opportunities that result in higher ROI. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/sales-team-blog-3.jpg" alt="" width="1906" height="459" /></p>

<h3 id="7-scalability-and-growth"><strong>7. Scalability and growth </strong></h3>

<p>Sales assistants provide scalability and flexibility to sales teams, particularly during periods of increased workload or growth. Adapting to changing demands allows the business to scale operations and handle higher sales volumes effectively.</p>

<p>Remember our imaginary corporation from earlier? By bringing sales assistants on board, the sales team experiences immediate relief as they can offload time-consuming administrative tasks and focus more on revenue-generating activities. The sales assistants quickly prove their value by identifying new leads, qualifying prospects, and providing prompt customer support—their contribution results in increased sales productivity, improved customer satisfaction, and faster sales cycle times. </p>

<p>As a result of the sales assistants’ support, ABC Corporation successfully scales its sales operations. The business can now handle a larger volume of leads, expand into new markets, and provide exceptional customer service while sustaining business growth. The sales team can pursue new opportunities and achieve higher sales targets, ultimately driving the company’s success in the competitive market. </p>

<h2 id="supercharge-your-pipeline"><strong>Supercharge your pipeline </strong></h2>

<p>On average, sales companies spend $97,960 to <a href="https://taskdrive.com/sales/sales-statistics/" target="_blank">replace a sales representative</a>. On top of that, filling a vacancy can take between 3.5 and 5.5 months. Outsourcing your sales assistants or sales team can be a cost-effective solution. </p>

<p><a href="https://influx.com/solutions/sales-assistants" target="_blank">Influx sales assistants</a> help chase down leads, allowing you to close more qualified deals. Our <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/dedicated-sales-teams" target="_blank">dedicated sales teams</a> offer a robust solution that provides an extra layer of sales support with all management and training included. <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/sales-assistants" target="_blank">Get a quote</a> to find out how to leverage Influx to scale and boost your sales. </p>]]></content><author><name>Mikayla Fuller</name></author><category term="business operations" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine this scenario: ABC Corporation, a rapidly growing technology company, has recently launched an innovative software solution that has gained significant traction in the market. The company’s sales team has been working tirelessly to capitalize on the product’s success and drive sales. However, as demand surges and the customer base expands, they need help to keep up with the workload. ]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building or scaling a customer support team</title><link href="https://influx.com/blog/building-customer-support-team" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building or scaling a customer support team" /><published>2023-05-11T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-11T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/building-or-scaling-customer-support-teams</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://influx.com/blog/building-customer-support-team"><![CDATA[<p>Building or scaling <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/customer-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">customer support</a> is a critical endeavor for businesses aiming to provide exceptional customer service. As a business grows, customer support needs to grow in tandem to ensure that customers continue to receive the same level of service and attention. Whether you’re starting from scratch or <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/customer-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">expanding an existing support system</a>, we have the answers! </p>

<h2 id="what-is-customer-support"><strong>What is customer support? </strong></h2>

<p>Customer support is the team of people who provide guidance and solutions when customers need assistance regarding a product or service. Customer support professionals — also known as representatives or agents — commonly aid customers via email, phone, chat, or social media conversations. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/1-79.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h2 id="main-types-of-customer-support"><strong>Main types of customer support</strong></h2>

<h3 id="1-voice-support"><strong>1. Voice support </strong></h3>

<p><a href="https://influx.com/solutions/voice-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Voice support</a> — also known as phone support or call center support — is a customer support method that involves communication with customers through voice or telephone conversations. As a form of real-time communication, customers can reach out to support representatives via phone calls. </p>

<h3 id="2-in-person"><strong>2. In-person</strong></h3>

<p>In-person support refers to providing direct assistance to customers through face-to-face interactions at physical locations. This type of support often involves showcasing products, demonstrating functionality, or providing product samples. </p>

<h3 id="3-email-support"><strong>3. Email support </strong></h3>

<p>Email support involves customers contacting support teams via email, allowing asynchronous communication and responses within a designated timeframe. While email support may not offer immediate or real-time interactions, it has its advantages. Customers have the convenience of submitting inquiries at any time. </p>

<h3 id="4-live-chat-support"><strong>4. Live chat support </strong></h3>

<p><a href="https://influx.com/solutions/live-chat-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Live chat support</a> is text-based communication that customers can utilize for real-time solutions. Chat support has become increasingly popular due to its efficiency, convenience, and because some customers prefer it to phone calls or emails. Because chat support is accessible through various channels — including company websites, mobile apps, or dedicated chat support platforms — it allows flexibility for customers to seek assistance from different devices or platforms. </p>

<p>Our <a href="https://influx.com/blog/live-chat-guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener">live chat support guide</a> offers a comprehensive sweep of all things live chat. </p>

<h3 id="5-self-service"><strong>5. Self-service </strong></h3>

<p>Self-service support empowers customers to find solutions or answers to their inquiries independently. It includes resources such as knowledge bases, FAQs, tutorials, user manuals, and online forums where customers can access information and troubleshoot problems on their own. </p>

<h3 id="6-social-media-support"><strong>6. Social media support</strong></h3>

<p><a href="https://influx.com/solutions/social-media-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Social media support</a> is an opportunity to connect with their customers on various social media platforms. Customers can reach out through DMs or comments, and receive assistance through public or private support. </p>

<p>Although there are many different types of customer support, businesses often combine different support channels to cater to diverse customer needs and preferences. Understanding the target audience, considering the complexity of products or services, and continuously gathering customer feedback can help businesses determine the most effective support strategy to provide customers with an exceptional experience. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/3-70.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h2 id="benefits-of-customer-support"><strong>Benefits of customer support </strong></h2>

<p>Customer support plays a crucial role in the success and growth of a business. Here are some key benefits of providing effective customer support: </p>

<ul>
  <li>Retention and loyalty: 89% of consumers are more likely to make another purchase after a positive customer service experience. (Salesforce Research)</li>
  <li>Customer acquisition and brand reputation: A good customer support experience can influence recommendations. Consumers who rate a company’s service as ‘good’ are 38% more likely to recommend that company. (Qualtrics XM Institute)</li>
  <li>Increased revenue: Businesses can grow revenue between 4-8% above their market when prioritizing better customer service experiences. (Bain &amp; Company) </li>
  <li>Customer satisfaction: 90% of customers rate an ‘immediate’ response as important or very important when they have a customer service question, and about 60% of customers define ‘immediate’ as 10 minutes or less. (Hubspot) </li>
</ul>

<p>Recognizing the importance of customer support and investing in the necessary resources and training, businesses can reap these benefits and create a customer-centric culture that drives long-term success. </p>

<p>Looking to elevate your customer support experience? Influx solutions are flexible to fit your needs. <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/customer-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Get in touch</a>! </p>

<h2 id="ais-impact-on-customer-support"><strong>AI’s impact on customer support</strong></h2>

<p>Artificial Intelligence (AI) has significantly impacted customer support, revolutionizing how businesses interact with their customers. From automation to predictive analysis, companies can reduce labor costs, increase efficiency, automatically collect customer information, and forecast future trends. While AI has transformed customer support, it’s still important to balance automation and human interaction. Integrating AI with human support agents can provide a seamless experience that combines the benefits of automation with the expertise and empathy of human agents. </p>

<h2 id="building-a-team-of-customer-support-specialists"><strong>Building a team of customer support specialists </strong></h2>

<p>A good customer support team possesses several key qualities and characteristics that contribute to their effectiveness in delivering exceptional customer service, such as excellent communication skills, product and service knowledge, empathy, and professionalism. Customer support agents should also be trained on <a href="https://influx.com/blog/how-to-deescalate-angry-customer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">de-escalation techniques</a> to diffuse an angry customer. </p>

<p>Building a team of customer support specialists is a patient and ongoing process that involves recruiting, <a href="https://influx.com/blog/customer-service-training" target="_blank" rel="noopener">training</a>, evaluating performance, and adapting strategies based on customers’ feedback and evolving business needs. The cost of building a team of support professionals can vary, but some expenses include salaries, technology, facilities and equipment, and management. Check out <a href="https://influx.com/blog/budget-friendly-customer-support-team" target="_blank" rel="noopener">how to build a great CX/support team on a budget</a> for more! </p>

<p>Because of the expenses associated with in-house hiring, outsourcing customer support to specialized service providers or utilizing remote teams can sometimes offer cost-effective alternatives. Influx provides fully managed, omnichannel support teams with pay-as-you-go pricing. <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/customer-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Get a quote</a>! </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/2-90.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h2 id="hiring-vs-outsourcing-customer-support"><strong>Hiring vs. outsourcing customer support </strong></h2>

<p>Before building or scaling your customer support team, there are two roads to consider: hiring in-house or outsourcing. Both options have pros and cons, but the right choice depends on what a business’s needs and goals are. We’ve created a breakdown of the advantages and disadvantages to consider in our <a href="https://influx.com/blog/hiring-vs-outsourcing-pros-and-cons">hiring vs. outsourcing</a> resource. </p>

<h2 id="how-to-provide-excellent-experiences"><strong>How to provide excellent experiences </strong></h2>

<p>Providing excellent customer service is like celebrating a birthday. Aligning these, you’d find similarities in attention to detail, going above and beyond to make their day special, evoking positive emotions, and fostering a memorable event that leaves an impression. </p>

<p>Just like you’d throw a Jurassic Park-themed party for your cousin who loves dinosaurs, but you’d host a different party for your cousin who loves disco. In exceptional customer support, interactions should be personalized, whether or not it’s a customer’s birthday. </p>

<h2 id="customer-support-where-every-interaction-is-a-celebration"><strong>Customer support: where every interaction is a celebration </strong></h2>

<p>Read our <a href="https://influx.com/blog/case-studies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">case studies</a> to see how brands work with Influx to deliver high-quality support that meets business and customer needs. <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/customer-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Get a customer support quote now</a>!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mikayla Fuller</name></author><category term="customer support" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building or scaling customer support is a critical endeavor for businesses aiming to provide exceptional customer service. As a business grows, customer support needs to grow in tandem to ensure that customers continue to receive the same level of service and attention. Whether you’re starting from scratch or expanding an existing support system, we have the answers! ]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bunk1 case study: 8 dedicated agents handle 5,000 tickets/month with 56% decrease in missed calls</title><link href="https://influx.com/blog/bunk1-togetherwork-case-study" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bunk1 case study: 8 dedicated agents handle 5,000 tickets/month with 56% decrease in missed calls" /><published>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/bunk1-case-study-8-dedicated-agents-handle-5-000-tickets-month-with-56-decrease-in-missed-calls</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://influx.com/blog/bunk1-togetherwork-case-study"><![CDATA[<h2 id="about-bunk1-by-togetherwork">About Bunk1 by Togetherwork:</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.bunk1.com/">Bunk1</a> is an online platform used by summer camps across the United States and Canada that offers families a simple way of staying connected with their campers. It’s also used as a camp management module for camp administrators. The brand was acquired by Togetherwork, a group management software and payment company that has experienced tremendous growth over the past few years.</p>

<p>With Bunk1, families can access secure online photo galleries with automated camper photo tagging, send printed notes to their camper, read daily newsletters, and watch videos from camp from a desktop browser and the easy-to-use mobile app for iOS and Android devices.</p>

<h2 id="influx-team-setup">Influx team setup:</h2>

<ul>
  <li>8 <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/dedicated-support-teams" target="_blank">dedicated agents</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://influx.com/solutions/voice-support" target="_blank">Voice support</a>, email, and in-app coverage</li>
  <li>US coverage: 12 hrs/7 days a week</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="influx-team-results">Influx team results:</h2>

<ul>
  <li>56% decrease in missed calls</li>
  <li>11% <a href="https://influx.com/improve-csat">CSAT increase</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://influx.com/clear-the-inbox" target="_blank">Inbox zero</a> achieved weekly</li>
  <li>Scaled from 1 agent to 8 agents</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="getting-started-with-influx">Getting started with Influx:</h2>

<p>Bunk1 came to Influx ready to ramp up customer support for peak season from May-August when ticket spikes hit 5,000 tickets/month on average. The brand needed a support team to handle increased coverage and allow their internal team to focus on the business. </p>

<p>Within a month, Bunk1 scaled from 1 dedicated agent to 8 dedicated agents to handle 50 tickets/day for voice support, email, and in-app coverage. The brand easily <a href="https://influx.com/scalable-support-operations" target="_blank">scaled up</a> to 8 agents for peak season and down to 2 agents as the summer wrapped up in August. </p>

<h2 id="what-theyre-saying-about-influx">What they’re saying about Influx:</h2>

<p><em>“Bunk1 has experienced serious growth and wanted a customer support partner that could handle summer ticket spikes when camps are in session. It was great to start off with one agent and increase that number as needed.</em></p>

<p><em>Influx was easy to work with and quickly trained more agents to meet our needs. Plus, we saw an increase in CSAT and decrease in missed calls!”</em></p>

<p>- Kathryn Hamilton, Senior Director of Operations at Togetherwork</p>

<h2 id="about-influx">About Influx: </h2>

<p>With pre-trained customer support professionals, 24/7 coverage and smart helpdesk integrations, we’re ready to step up your support within a week. Take charge of the inbox and free up your in-house team to do their best work. <a href="https://influx.com/get-a-quote" target="_blank">We’ll handle the rest.</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Graysen Christopher</name></author><category term="case studies" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[About Bunk1 by Togetherwork:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The role of social media presence for businesses</title><link href="https://influx.com/blog/the-role-of-social-media-presence-for-businesses" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The role of social media presence for businesses" /><published>2023-04-27T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-27T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/the-role-of-social-media-presence-for-businesses</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://influx.com/blog/the-role-of-social-media-presence-for-businesses"><![CDATA[<p><em>Social media necessitates immediate responses. Access 24/7 social media support that matches your brand voice.</em><a href="https://influx.com/solutions/social-media-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Get a quote</em></a><em>!</em></p>

<p>In my four-plus years as a Social Media Specialist creating content and managing platforms for clients in diverse industries, I’ve learned a thing or two about social media marketing and its impact on a business. Content creation is a time-consuming process that requires thought and structure. When employed efficiently, a strong content marketing strategy is one of the best ways a business can shape its brand, engage its audience, and <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/social-media-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">promptly resolve customer questions/concerns</a>. Let’s talk about how to grow your social media presence! </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/2-88.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h2 id="social-presence-is-essential-for-your-brand"><strong>Social presence is essential for your brand </strong></h2>

<p>In 1996, Bill Gates wrote an essay that altered the course of digital marketing. Titled “Content is King” (a phrase many are familiar with), he suggested a majority of the money generated online would come from content. Today, not only are brands benefitting from content, but individual creators are making a steady living and rising to fame from their content alone. This is proof of the power content has. According to Statista, </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In 2022, global content marketing industry revenue was estimated at roughly 63 billion U.S. dollars. The source projected that it would increase to 72 billion in 2023 and continue to grow in further years to reach 107 billion in 2026. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>Ranked by number of monthly active users, the top social media platforms are: </p>

<ul>
  <li>Facebook</li>
  <li>YouTube</li>
  <li>Instagram</li>
  <li>TikTok</li>
  <li>Douyin</li>
  <li>Snapchat</li>
</ul>

<p>With over 4.9 billion people accessing social media worldwide as of 2023 and an average social media user hopping between 6-7 social media platforms every month (Demand Sage), it’s easy to see why an online presence is essential for brands. Social media allows a business to showcase its products or services, <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/social-media-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">build relationships with customers</a>, and make it easier for potential customers to connect with a company. </p>

<p>Does your business need to be on all the major platforms? The short answer is no. It’s essential to focus on the platforms that are most relevant to your target audience and the nature of your business. This is especially true for smaller teams that may have limited resources. It’s better to have a strong presence on a few platforms than a weak presence on many. </p>

<p>As a cost-effective marketing strategy, having a solid social presence is a tool for much more than brand awareness. Social media enhances accessibility and enables businesses to reach a wider audience. Strategic content can grow your customer base and boost loyalty. If you’re looking for social media support, <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/social-media-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Influx can help</a>! </p>

<h2 id="examples-of-brands-that-have-successfully-found-their-niche"><strong>Examples of brands that have successfully found their niche</strong></h2>

<p>As someone who understands that content creation can be a painstaking effort, these are the top three social media accounts I respect. Take a look and note how they offer a diverse mix of content that perfectly fits their brand expectations. </p>

<h3 id="1-chipotle"><strong>1. Chipotle </strong></h3>

<p>Chipotle’s social media strategy is a prime example of keeping pace with ‘cultural shifts’ and making the most of trends. Chipotle’s content includes relevant memes, influencer marketing, user-generated content, engaging campaigns, and ‘unhinged’ yet carefully crafted posts. The Chipotle social media support team responds to customer comments with brand-appropriate replies and attaches their name to the end of the comment—a nice touch that conveys personable and genuine approachability. </p>

<h3 id="2-national-park-service"><strong>2. National Park Service </strong></h3>

<p>The National Parks Service is truly a wordsmith with captions. Just take its Instagram bio, for example, “Don’t pet the fluffy cows,” with an emoji of a bison. The Parks’ content is funny and informative, and accomplishes its goal of encouraging people to visit the National Parks. </p>

<h3 id="3-duolingo"><strong>3. Duolingo </strong></h3>

<p>Duolingo’s social media strategy is to entertain. Its mascot, a green owl named Duo, is cheeky and oftentimes approaches the line of being inappropriate without crossing it. Racking up over 6.6 million followers on TikTok, Duolingo stays relevant with its use of pop culture references and hilarious responses. Although Duolingo is a well-known business, its content helps keep them visible. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/3-69.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h2 id="8-proven-strategies-for-boosting-your-social-media-presence"><strong>8 proven strategies for boosting your social media presence </strong></h2>

<p>There isn’t a specific or ‘correct’ way to make social media content, and what works for one brand may not work for another. I’ve found the following strategies to be consistent all across the board, regardless of industry. </p>

<h3 id="1-structure-your-content-in-an-editorial-calendar"><strong>1. Structure your content in an editorial calendar </strong></h3>

<p>As previously stated, creating content is time-consuming and necessitates structure. I suggest a monthly editorial calendar to help keep things organized. A social media editorial calendar is a system of planning daily social media posts. This allows you to create a month’s worth of content, review posts for any grammatical errors, and see an overview of what you’re posting for the month to keep things fresh. </p>

<h3 id="2-use-memes-sparingly"><strong>2. Use memes sparingly</strong></h3>

<p>You may find it hard to believe, but every business and industry can utilize memes. I have chosen a tasty example below as a testament. (Image source: Seoulz) An occasional meme can increase engagement and get people talking. When creating memes, ensure that they are relatable and make sense. Relevant memes have the potential to go viral or at least get a laugh from your audience, which is valuable for reputation. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/meme.webp" alt="" width="700" height="344" /></p>

<h3 id="3-respond-immediately-and-keep-your-tone-of-voice-consistent"><strong>3. Respond immediately and keep your tone of voice consistent </strong></h3>

<p>Keeping your tone of voice consistent on social media is crucial to maintain your brand identity and to create a sense of familiarity with your audience. Consider the personality traits that define your brand and how you want to come across to your audience. </p>

<p>When responding to customer questions, it’s crucial to always maintain that voice. It’s also important to respond as quickly as possible. According to HubSpot, 39% of social media users expect a response within 60 minutes, yet the average response time for businesses is about five hours. Influx offers 24/7 social media support, so your customers don’t have to wait for a response. Increase your social media response time and <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/social-media-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">get a quote now</a>!</p>

<h3 id="4-create-shareable-content"><strong>4. Create shareable content </strong></h3>

<p>Shareable content grows your audience organically. It also means you posted something that other people want their followers to see—well done! To create shareable content, you’ll need to understand the interests and needs of your target audience and speak directly to them. The more relevant and valuable your content is to your audience, the more likely they are to share it. </p>

<h3 id="5-maintain-an-understanding-of-different-algorithms"><strong>5. Maintain an understanding of different algorithms </strong></h3>

<p>Social media is constantly evolving. Algorithms are fast-moving machines that require social media managers to stay up-to-date with changes and best practices. Social media algorithms determine which content is shown to users in their feeds and take a few things into account, such as the timing of posts and content that receives high engagement. By understanding how these algorithms work, you can create content that is more likely to be shown to your target audience, which increases reach and visibility. </p>

<h3 id="6-utilize-user-generated-content"><strong>6. Utilize user-generated content</strong></h3>

<p>User-generated content (UGC) is a valuable resource for businesses, as it builds customer trust and provides a fresh perspective on products or services. Consider creating a specific hashtag associated with your brand, and encourage followers to tag your account for the chance to be featured. It’s important to remember that you credit the original creator and obtain their permission to use their content. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/1-78.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h3 id="7-increase-video-content-"><strong>7. Increase video content  </strong></h3>

<p>TikTok is the fastest-growing social platform we’ve seen thus far. This resulted in an almost immediate reaction from Facebook and Instagram to introduce reels to keep up and stay relevant. Now, videos are the preferred choice of content consumption. Easier for our brains to process, video presents the perfect opportunity to engage your audience without a block of text to relay the same message. </p>

<h3 id="8-refer-to-content-buckets"><strong>8. Refer to content buckets</strong></h3>

<p>Brands often use six different content buckets—education, personal, entertainment, conversational, promotion, and inspiration. Almost any piece of content falls within these buckets. You lose followers, engagement, and momentum if your content becomes too flat. On the other hand, if your content has a mix of posts that switch up the focus to fit within these buckets, it keeps your audience engaged. </p>

<h2 id="boost-your-social-media-presence-with-expert-support"><strong>Boost your social media presence with expert support</strong></h2>

<p>We hope these tips come in handy to grow your social presence and would love to help you continue making the most of your social marketing efforts. With our round-the-clock support, you can rest assured that your brand’s social media customer service is in good hands. We match your brand voice across all social media platforms to ensure that your customers receive top-tier support right when needed. So why wait? <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/social-media-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Contact Influx today</a>, and let us help you take your social media presence to the next level!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mikayla Fuller</name></author><category term="resources and guides" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Social media necessitates immediate responses. Access 24/7 social media support that matches your brand voice.Get a quote!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The pros and cons of hiring vs. outsourcing</title><link href="https://influx.com/blog/hiring-vs-outsourcing-pros-and-cons" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The pros and cons of hiring vs. outsourcing" /><published>2023-04-20T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-20T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/the-pros-and-cons-of-hiring-vs-outsourcing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://influx.com/blog/hiring-vs-outsourcing-pros-and-cons"><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to expanding a business or taking on new projects, there’s a decision that companies often need to make: whether to hire new employees or outsource the work to an external company. Before making a decision, it’s essential to carefully consider your specific business needs and goals and then weigh the pros and cons of each option. We’ll cover the benefits and disadvantages in simple, digestible bullet points to help you make an informed decision that aligns with your expectations. </p>

<h2 id="the-benefits-of-outsourcing"><strong>The benefits of outsourcing </strong></h2>

<p>Outsourcing is the practice of hiring a third party to perform tasks or provide a service that would otherwise be done in-house. Compared to hiring, outsourcing offers a range of benefits that may align with your business’s needs. Here are some of the benefits: </p>

<ul>
  <li>The cost of hiring, training, and managing employees, as well as the infrastructure and equipment to keep a team productive, can quickly add up. Outsourcing is less expensive than hiring employees because you only pay for completed work rather than employee benefits, office space, and other overhead costs. According to Clutch, 59% of global companies rely on outsourcing to reduce costs. </li>
  <li>Outsourcing allows you to access specialized skills and expertise you may have yet to gain in-house. This can increase efficiency and improve quality. It also lets you find the best, most cost-effective option for your business. </li>
  <li>Outsourcing can provide flexibility to scale up or down as needed without the costs and risks associated with hiring or laying off employees. </li>
  <li>Outsourcing can improve competitiveness by offering better quality and lower costs while allowing you to focus on strategic initiatives that can drive growth and innovation. </li>
  <li>By leveraging the expertise of specialized service providers, outsourcing can help mitigate risks associated with in-house operations, such as regulatory compliance and security breaches. </li>
</ul>

<p>If outsourcing is an option you’re exploring, we would love to chat and walk you through any questions you might have about the various <a href="https://influx.com/solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener">support solutions</a> Influx offers. Maximize your budget with pay-as-you-go pricing that includes all training and management. Our full-service teams are on-demand and ready to help. <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/how-it-works" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Get in touch now</a>! </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/2-87.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h2 id="the-benefits-of-hiring"><strong>The benefits of hiring</strong></h2>

<p>Although hiring might be more expensive than outsourcing, it can be a long-term investment for your company. Here are some of the other benefits that come with hiring: </p>

<ul>
  <li>When you hire employees, you have more control over the work they do and how they do it. You can provide specific instructions, make suggestions, and monitor progress. </li>
  <li>Hiring employees gives you the opportunity to select candidates who align with your company’s culture and values. This can help you create a cohesive team that works well together and shares common goals. </li>
  <li>Employees who are invested in your company and its success are more likely to be loyal and committed to their work. They are also more likely to stay with your company long-term, reducing turnover costs and maintaining institutional knowledge. </li>
  <li>Hiring employees can give you more control over your staff’s skills and expertise, enabling you to build a team with diverse talent. </li>
</ul>

<p>Whether to hire or outsource depends on your specific business needs and goals. Understanding the disadvantages of each may help guide you toward the right option. </p>

<h2 id="the-disadvantages-of-outsourcing"><strong>The disadvantages of outsourcing</strong></h2>

<p>Despite the many benefits of outsourcing, there are a few reasons businesses may choose to hire instead. Consider the following: </p>

<ul>
  <li>Working with an outsourced team can be more difficult because they may be in a different time zone or have other communication preferences than your in-house team.</li>
</ul>

<p>Influx has solved this problem using the ‘follow the sun’ model. This type of global workflow allows us to pass work between offices in different time zones to increase responsiveness and reduce delays. </p>

<ul>
  <li>When you outsource a task or process to a third party, you give up control over how the task is performed. This can be problematic if the work is critical to your business operations and requires a high level of quality control. </li>
</ul>

<p>Outsourcing with Influx promises the utmost care and attention. We use custom reports to track agent success and compare their performance to benchmarks we create with you during the third phase of our onboarding process. Influx provides consistent, high-quality support in a simple month-to-month format. </p>

<ul>
  <li>While outsourcing can be cost-effective in some cases, it can also be expensive depending on whom you outsource with. </li>
</ul>

<p>All of our plans include training and management with no setup fees. Our simple, pay-as-you-go model matches cost with revenue, and we won’t tack on any hidden or extra fees. For exact pricing breakdowns, <a href="https://influx.com/pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">get in touch</a>! </p>

<p>Although outsourcing has disadvantages, hiring also comes with its cons that should be carefully considered. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/3-67.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h2 id="the-disadvantages-of-hiring"><strong>The disadvantages of hiring</strong></h2>

<p>The BLS puts the median number of years that wage and salary workers have been with their current employer at 4.1 years. Compared to outsourcing, there are several disadvantages to hiring employees, which businesses should be aware of before making a decision. Some of the disadvantages include the following: </p>

<ul>
  <li>When you hire employees, you are committed to paying them for a certain period, regardless of your company’s workload. This can lead to overstaffing during slower periods or understaffing during busier times. Outsourcing can offer more flexibility to scale with you. </li>
  <li>According to Gallup, the cost of replacing an individual employee can range from one-half to two times the employee’s salary. That means losing an employee with an annual salary of $80,000 can cost your business up to $160,000.</li>
  <li>Finding and hiring the right employees can be a lengthy and challenging process. You may need to advertise job openings, sift through resumes, conduct interviews, and perform background checks. Outsourcing removes the concern for the recruitment process. </li>
  <li>When hiring, you will typically have a smaller pool of candidates. This means you have fewer options regarding both skill/experience and cost. This is even more applicable if remote work is not feasible for your business. </li>
</ul>

<p>There you have it; a breakdown of the pros and cons of hiring vs. outsourcing. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/1-76.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h2 id="when-to-hire-and-when-to-outsource"><strong> When to hire and when to outsource </strong></h2>

<p>Knowing when to hire and when to outsource is essential for success. Evaluate the level of expertise required and whether it is a skill readily available within your organization. You should also consider your budget and whether you can afford the costs associated with a full-time employee, including benefits, payroll taxes, and training costs. Ultimately, the decision to hire or outsource should be based on a careful assessment of your available resources and your business needs and circumstances. </p>

<h2 id="maximize-efficiency-minimize-costs-and-outsource-with-confidence"><strong>Maximize efficiency, minimize costs, and outsource with confidence</strong></h2>

<p>We welcome you to read through our <a href="https://influx.com/blog/case-studies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">case studies</a> to discover how brands like yours are working with Influx to achieve desired outcomes. Outsourcing to a trusted team of experts can free up your time and resources, allowing you to focus on critical aspects of your business. Reduce operational costs and remain competitive in today’s fast-paced environment. <a href="https://influx.com/solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Find your support solution now</a>!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mikayla Fuller</name></author><category term="business operations" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When it comes to expanding a business or taking on new projects, there’s a decision that companies often need to make: whether to hire new employees or outsource the work to an external company. Before making a decision, it’s essential to carefully consider your specific business needs and goals and then weigh the pros and cons of each option. We’ll cover the benefits and disadvantages in simple, digestible bullet points to help you make an informed decision that aligns with your expectations. ]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to cut business costs without lowering quality</title><link href="https://influx.com/blog/cost-cutting-strategies-to-maintain-quality" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to cut business costs without lowering quality" /><published>2023-04-13T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-13T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://influx.com/blog/how-to-cut-business-costs-without-lowering-quality</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://influx.com/blog/cost-cutting-strategies-to-maintain-quality"><![CDATA[<p><em>Looking to reduce costs without sacrificing quality? </em><a href="https://influx.com/solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Outsource with Influx</em></a><em>; the simple solution! </em></p>

<p>Reducing expenses is on your mind if your business has been impacted by supply chain disruptions, reduced demand, or increasing costs. Rethinking strategies and adapting to changing circumstances are mandatory to maintain profitability. </p>

<p>Cost-cutting can sometimes come at the cost of quality. However, with careful planning, it is possible to cut business costs without compromising quality. As a result, many businesses are exploring options such as outsourcing with companies like <a href="https://influx.com/solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Influx</a> to reduce labor costs and improve efficiency. This blog will discuss practical ways to reduce costs without sacrificing quality. </p>

<h2 id="7-cost-cutting-strategies-that-preserve-quality"><strong>7 cost-cutting strategies that preserve quality </strong></h2>

<h3 id="1-outsource-non-core-activities"><strong>1. Outsource non-core activities </strong></h3>

<p>According to Paycor, labor costs can account for as much as 70% of total business costs, including wages, benefits, payroll, and other related taxes. Despite this, HR professionals only spend 15% of their time managing the cost of labor. </p>

<p>For many businesses, labor costs are controllable, but only to a certain extent. The wages of highly skilled individuals come with a price, and the value/cost of their efforts only increases with time. Reducing labor expenses without laying off team members can be challenging. Outsourcing non-core activities is the preferred solution that maintains high quality while reducing costs. </p>

<p>Instead of recruiting, hiring, and onboarding individuals, outsourcing provides you with a team of experts already trained in the latest technologies. Outsourcing saves you time from managing the responsibilities of an entire team and allows you to free up resources to focus on other critical tasks. </p>

<p>As leaders in the customer support outsourcing world, we work with companies to deliver flexibility and scale. With all management and training included, we use three levels: local, client-specific, and data-driven, to manage and improve performance autonomously. <a href="https://influx.com/blog/case-studies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">See how brands work with Influx</a> to deliver fast, high-quality support at scale. </p>

<p>We offer simple, pay-as-you-go pricing to maximize your budget and returns. Our team is ready to launch in only one week. <a href="https://influx.com/solutions/how-it-works" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Learn how it works now</a>!</p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/3-66.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h3 id="2-analyze-your-expenses"><strong>2. Analyze your expenses </strong></h3>

<p>Are there any idle services or software chipping away at your budget? Are you wasting money on pricey tools when there are affordable alternatives? </p>

<p>Understanding your budget means digging deep into where exactly it’s going. Maybe this means setting aside time for a budget breakdown to ensure that the right portion of your budget is within estimates. Perhaps this means considering the value of certain expenses and if their benefits are worth the cost. Look for expenses that are not essential to your business operations and consider cutting them. </p>

<h3 id="3-negotiate-with-vendors"><strong>3. Negotiate with vendors </strong></h3>

<p>Negotiating with a vendor can help you get better pricing and contract terms. This can help you reduce your expenses and improve your bottom line. Negotiations are commonly used to determine the best price and payment terms, as well as delivery and production times, quality standards, and other factors. </p>

<p>If you have established relationships with vendors, consider negotiating for better prices on the products and services you need. You can get discounts by agreeing to longer-term contracts or increasing your order quantities. Remember, negotiating is a two-way street. It’s essential to approach negotiations collaboratively, focusing on finding a mutually beneficial solution rather than simply trying to win the negotiation. </p>

<p>Overall, negotiating with vendors can help you save money and manage your expenses more effectively, improving your business’s financial health and performance. </p>

<h3 id="4-improve-efficiency"><strong>4. Improve efficiency </strong></h3>

<p>Automating business processes can help you reduce labor costs while maintaining the same level of quality. Consider using software tools to streamline your workflows and improve efficiency. We’ve written another blog on the <a href="https://influx.com/blog/automation-employee-productivity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">role of automation</a> in employee productivity and how it can benefit your budget. Check it out for more on automating for efficiency! </p>

<p>Spending less time on tasks or projects makes room for a higher quantity of work that costs less to maintain. This leads us to our next cost-saving strategy. </p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/2-86.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h3 id="5-switch-to-remote-work"><strong>5. Switch to remote work </strong></h3>

<p>According to Go Remotely, more than two-thirds of employers have seen increased productivity among remote workers. Specific examples include companies like Dow Chemical, Best Buy, and British Telecom which have seen a 35% to 40% increase in employee productivity among their remote workers. </p>

<p>Here at Influx, we’re big supporters of remote work. In fact, our entire team is remote, and the <a href="https://influx.com/blog/remote-work-how-to-make-it-work" target="_blank" rel="noopener">benefits</a> have allowed us to save on overhead expenses such as office space and utilities. Consider allowing your employees to work from home or implement a flexible schedule to increase productivity and save on business expenses. </p>

<h3 id="6-focus-marketing"><strong>6. Focus marketing </strong></h3>

<p>Maximizing your marketing expenses is a great way to save costs while promoting your business effectively. Here are a few tips for doing so: </p>

<ul>
  <li>Leverage free marketing tools</li>
  <li>Choose the right marketing channels </li>
  <li>Identify and strive to reach your target audience </li>
  <li>Test and refine your strategy </li>
  <li>Measure your results </li>
</ul>

<p>The standard rule of thumb for marketing ROI is a 5:1 ratio, with exceptional return on investment (ROI) considered around a 10:1 ratio. Anything less than a 2:1 ratio is considered unprofitable, as the costs of producing and distributing goods/services frequently result in organizations breaking even with their spending and returns.</p>

<p>Effective marketing should bring in enough ROI to make it worth the expense. If you aren’t seeing solid results from your marketing efforts, consider making adjustments.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/uploads/1-74.png" alt="" width="700" height="300" /></p>

<h3 id="7-make-cost-cutting-an-ongoing-process"><strong>7. Make cost-cutting an ongoing process </strong></h3>

<p>Whether you set cost-cutting goals or track and analyze spending regularly, cost-cutting should be an integral part of your business practices. Embrace technology and continuously improve processes. It is essential to periodically review and adjust your cost-cutting strategy based on your business needs and goals. By making cost-cutting an ongoing process, you can optimize your business operations and maintain profitability over the long term. </p>

<h2 id="reduce-costs-with-reliable-outsourcing"><strong>Reduce costs with reliable outsourcing </strong></h2>

<p>We offer access to a diverse pool of highly skilled professionals who can deliver high-quality work at a <a href="https://influx.com/pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">competitive cost</a>. Our team uses modern technology and tools to streamline processes and increase efficiency, ultimately reducing costs for our clients. Our rigorous quality control process ensures that the work delivered meets or exceeds our clients’ expectations. </p>

<p>With 24/7 support and pay-as-you-go pricing, we ensure that our clients’ needs are met promptly and efficiently. <a href="https://influx.com/solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Browse our support solutions</a> to see how we can help you cut costs and maintain quality! </p>]]></content><author><name>Mikayla Fuller</name></author><category term="business operations" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking to reduce costs without sacrificing quality? Outsource with Influx; the simple solution! ]]></summary></entry></feed>